Tatiana Shchelokova

Student at Udacity

tanyacholokova@gmail.com

Summary

Entry-level front-end developer specializes in developing client-side web applications using HTML, CSS and JavaScript. Skills & Languages: HTML & CSS (including Bootstrap), JavaScript, jQuery, HTML5 Canvas, Critical Rendering Path, 60FPS Rendering, JavaScript Web App Frameworks (Knockout), JavaScript Testing Frameworks (Jasmine), Object-Oriented Programming, Chrome Developer Tools

Experience

Lead engineer at Siberian State Metallurgical University

October 2005 - May 2006 (8 months)

Support of computer facilities of department. Supervise students. Research support, and conferencing planning and coordination.

Head of trading department at "Buhgalter" ZAO (office supply retailer)

May 2000 - April 2001 (1 year)

Staff management: recruitment, instruction, ongoing training. Purchase of goods, inventory management, expansion of product variety, competitors monitoring. Search for new vendors, search for new wholesale customers, communication with vendors and customers.

Store manager at "Kuznetsk snabsbyt" ZAO (plumbing supply retailer)

December 1996 - May 2000 (3 years 6 months)

Staff management: recruitment, instruction, ongoing training. Purchase of goods, inventory management, expansion of product variety, competitors monitoring. Search for new vendors, search for new wholesale customers, communication with vendors and customers.

Engineer at Western Siberian metallurgical integrated plant

August 1991 - October 1997 (6 years 3 months)

Condition monitoring of lining of metallurgical furnaces. Laboratory research and development of new solutions of lining for metallurgical furnaces. Research on lining resistance improvement.

Skills & Expertise

JavaScript HTML5 HTML CSS **SQL**

Microsoft Office

jQuery

KnockoutJS

Bootstrap

JavaScript Testing Frameworks

Education

Udacity

Front-End Nanodegree, 2014 - 2015

Siberian State Metallurgical University

Programming and information networks, 2005 - 2005

Siberian Metallurgical Institute

Engineer's degree, Heat engineering and industrial ecology of metallurgical manufacturing., 1986 - 1991

Projects

Neighborhood Map

June 2015 to Present

Members: Tatiana Shchelokova

Single-page, responsive application built with Knockout.js framework and hosted on GitHub Pages. Developed a full-page map that loads with 20 popular bars and restaurants in Gaithersburg, MD. User can view recent information taken at each location (retrieved by AJAX request to Yelp API).

Arcade Game Clone

March 2015 to Present

Members: Tatiana Shchelokova

Clone of the classic game, Frogger. Udacity provided the art assets and game engine. Coded player, enemies, and other game entities in JavaScript's object-oriented pseudo-classical style. Created enemy subclasses with different movement patterns and sprites (edited art assets in GIMP).

Website Optimization

April 2015 to Present

Members: Tatiana Shchelokova

Optimized critical rendering path of existing website to achieve PageSpeed Insights score above 90. Eliminated inefficiencies in the website's scroll animation. Site now scrolls at 60 frames per second.

Tatiana Shchelokova

Student at Udacity

tanyacholokova@gmail.com



Contact Tatiana on LinkedIn